Name: Yusuf Bilal Ubangida

Address: 5, Agbaje street, off Doyin-omololu, Alapere, Ketu, Lagos
Phone: 08029336571
E-mail: ubahyusuf484@gmail.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/bilal-yusuf-450871199

Professional Profile

Dedicated multidisciplinary engineer and web developer with three years of experience in website design and database administration, strong creative & analytical skills and a team player with an eye for detail. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL.

Education

school: University of Ilorin

Course: Electrical and Electronics engineering

• Tenure: 2017-2022

Core Skills

- Full Software development cycle
- Development of Test frameworks
- Web technologies e.g. HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Typescript
- Server-side programming language e.g. PHP
- MySQL databases for management and storage of data
- Also proficient in the Microsoft office suite e.g. Word, Excel, PowerPoint etc.

Other Skills

- Adequate Knowledge of Python, C, C++, JavaScript frameworks such as Reactjs, Nodejs, jQuery
- Adequate Knowledge of Solidity

Work Experience

Internship (August 2017 – date) Advanced Technology Limited (23b, Adeola-Odeku street, Victoria Island, Lagos)

 Working occasionally in developing web solutions for stockbroking companies using HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Freelance full stack developer (September 2019 – date) Freelance

- Developing web applications for Cooperative societies using web technologies such as HTML, CSS to design webpages, forms, tables etc.
- Used server-side technology such as PHP for form processing, applying CRUD functions to work with MYSQL database records
- Using MySQL to store user data and transactions
- Used AJAX to asynchronously update webpages, request data from server without reloading webpage